<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postop (SRS) Care 101</title>
    <description>Tips and tricks to help on your recovery from MTF SRS</description>
    <link>http://postopcare.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://postopcare.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 17:53:54 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 17:53:54 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>SRS packing List</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-its-almost-time-to-leave-for-srs-and-youre-wondering-whats-good-to-pack-the-following-is-a-generic-list-of-stuff-most-postop-persons-found-useful-and-neccessary-on-their-journey-to-anatomial-womanhood&quot;&gt;So it’s almost time to leave for SRS and you’re wondering what’s good to pack? The following is a generic list of stuff most postop persons found useful and neccessary on their journey to anatomial womanhood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tech-stuff&quot;&gt;Tech Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A tablet or a laptop to communicate with folks back home. If traveling light, at least a mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to bring the required power socket adapters and voltage transformers so that your tech stays juiced. It is very miserable running out of battery energy when you are down wounded.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some women chose to bring a gaming console, especially if they weren’t traveling alone. I personally enjoyed playing the XBox with my friend from Europe who had brought her own xBox along. Also, I kicked her butt at Street Fighter, thanks to my Asian genes /sarcasm.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;WiFi repeater if you are techy and WiFi is free. Configure it in your room before surgery though, it is not that easy focusing or doing things after surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A camera if shooting from your mobile phone isn’t your thing. Or get one of those fancy phones with really great cameras built in.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A pair of earphones or earbuds to plug in and cancel external noise whether on the plane or in recovery or whenever it gets too stressful&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A spare mobile phone if traveling overseas and intending to have a local SIM card&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;surgery-care-stuff&quot;&gt;Surgery Care Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Buy overnight sanitary pads (as long and big as you like) at the location. Buying from home might be unneccsarily heavy or onerous.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A diaper changing mat. Diaper mats are easy to clean, which makes it suitable for dilating on, and for sleeping upon, to prevent bedsheet staining (the costs of cleanup most likelt to be borne by you)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Neosporin or topical antiseptic which is allowed by your own doctor, to help wound recovery&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A small spray-bottle capable of being refilled with betadine, for easy, effective and efficient dispensation of Betadine onto site&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It is a Good Idea to find out the costs of lube back home, for a comparison against prices provided by the surgical facility or by a local pharmacy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Getting a small container around 5 inches wide can help you hold used dilators within especically if they’re icky with lube . This way they won’t get on your bedding or the floor or get dirty.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;clothes&quot;&gt;Clothes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Plenty of loose underwear, about 1.5 per day for each day stay.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Loose skirts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Loose pants (not recommended)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bras, tops, etc&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Other climate-specific gear suitable for the climate you are entering, including shoes and scarves.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;toiletries&quot;&gt;Toiletries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Toothbrush and toothpaste&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Personal grooming kit such as razors , creams, makeup, hairbrushes, etc&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spare kitchen towels or toilet paper for just in case&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;wet wipes or baby wipes – lifesaver.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hair ties are useful especially if showering isn’t permitted for the first few days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;misc-stuff&quot;&gt;Misc Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sunglasses&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spare zipper bags&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mom/Dad/relative&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A big cloth-based bag for the donut. It’s less conspicuous and makes it easier to carry and also easier to clean, too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 07:59:59 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/surgery/2015/08/11/SRS-Packing-List/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/surgery/2015/08/11/SRS-Packing-List/</guid>
        
        <category>packing</category>
        
        <category>preparation</category>
        
        
        <category>surgery</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ice Cream Cold Compress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I only just discovered that a recent postop/post-orchi candidate can use a tub of ice cream as cold compress over the wound. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice cream can also be eaten when while being used, too, which is pretty cool (haha, punny). Captain Obvious says: That's a real morale booster in times of pain
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 07:59:59 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/orchi,/surgery/2015/08/02/ice-cream-cold-compress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/orchi,/surgery/2015/08/02/ice-cream-cold-compress/</guid>
        
        <category>orchi</category>
        
        
        <category>orchi,</category>
        
        <category>surgery</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vaginal Flora</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;nobody-likes-a-smelly-vag-not-even-ourselves&quot;&gt;Nobody likes a smelly vag, not even ourselves&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newly installed neovagina and neovulva do not have the flora native to natal vulvas and ladybits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because throughout the process of surgery and aftercare, the surgeons douse us liberally with antiseptics to prevent infection, and thereafter, we are usually on a dose of antibiotics, which presumably kill off almost &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; flora…except the stinky ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One sure sign that we are getting a yeast infection is an unpleasant smell. If our vag stinks like ass, a rotten fish, or even marmite / vegemite, it’s likely we got ourselves a B.V. aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bacterial_vaginosis&quot;&gt;bacterial vaginosis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately one of the &lt;em&gt;leading causes&lt;/em&gt; of B.V. is douching. Yup, that activity that surgeons sometimes encourage us to do to flush stuff out. It gets particularly bad if we use betadine or even vinegar as douching solutions because these stuff nuke our good flora along with the bad. The antibiotics we’re usually hopped up on postop don’t help much, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need more acidophilus types in there, not less. There’s one good solution, which is to buy Intimate Hygiene Washes, particularly those with prebiotics or probiotics in them. The really high-end washes are pretty pricy and come in a foaming bottle but we can buy a foam-making bottle and pour (diluted) washing solution in there to max out our money, because the washing instructions pretty much always instruct users to foam before applying, which is tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy those at Walmart for less than $5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I’ve made my small bottle last me a whole six months, washing twice a day!$5 never went anywhere as far in my life as this)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advantages-of-not-being-malodorous&quot;&gt;Advantages of not being malodorous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mental Well-being – we can be further in harmony with our new anatomy after our painful rebirth, be more confident and not be so paranoid everyone is smelling fish when we enter the room.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Better physical well-being – yes, not having a rash or stinky discharge is pretty nice, plus we don’t have to scrub our undies that hard. whew.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Better love life – most lovers prefer ladybits which don’t smell offensive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-should-we-start-or-when-is-it-okay-to-use-a-vaginal-wash&quot;&gt;When should we start or when is it okay to use a vaginal wash?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise indicated by your doctor, a good time would be pretty close to the end of your antiobiotic dosage, or when the offensive smell / discharge starts to appear, or when your stitches stop oozing. Usually that would be around the 6 week mark upwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also never too late to use a vaginal wash, no matter how many years postop a person is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please report on your results after trying this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/health/2015/07/27/VaginalFlora/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/health/2015/07/27/VaginalFlora/</guid>
        
        <category>flora</category>
        
        <category>feminine</category>
        
        <category>hygiene</category>
        
        <category>wash</category>
        
        
        <category>health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Postopcare 101</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A community driven effort to share tips and tricks for the initial MTF SRS postop recovery period.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 23:24:44 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/introduction/2015/07/26/welcome-to-postopcare/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/introduction/2015/07/26/welcome-to-postopcare/</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
