<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postop (SRS) Care 101</title>
    <description>Tips and tricks to help on your recovery from MTF SRS</description>
    <link>http://postopcare.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://postopcare.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 22:50:50 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 22:50:50 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ice Cream Cold Compress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I only just discovered that a recent postop/post-orchi candidate can use a tub of ice cream as cold compress over the wound. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice cream can also be eaten when while being used, too, which is pretty cool (haha, punny). Captain Obvious says: That's a real morale booster in times of pain
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 07:59:59 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/orchi,/surgery/2015/08/02/ice-cream-cold-compress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/orchi,/surgery/2015/08/02/ice-cream-cold-compress/</guid>
        
        <category>orchi</category>
        
        
        <category>orchi,</category>
        
        <category>surgery</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vaginal Flora</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;nobody-likes-a-smelly-vag-not-even-ourselves&quot;&gt;Nobody likes a smelly vag, not even ourselves&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our newly installed neovagina and neovulva do not have the flora native to natal vulvas and ladybits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because throughout the process of surgery and aftercare, the surgeons douse us liberally with antiseptics to prevent infection, and thereafter, we are usually on a dose of antibiotics, which presumably kill off almost &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; flora…except the stinky ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One sure sign that we are getting a yeast infection is an unpleasant smell. If our vag stinks like ass, a rotten fish, or even marmite / vegemite, it’s likely we got ourselves a B.V. aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bacterial_vaginosis&quot;&gt;bacterial vaginosis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately one of the &lt;em&gt;leading causes&lt;/em&gt; of B.V. is douching. Yup, that activity that surgeons sometimes encourage us to do to flush stuff out. It gets particularly bad if we use betadine or even vinegar as douching solutions because these stuff nuke our good flora along with the bad. The antibiotics we’re usually hopped up on postop don’t help much, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need more acidophilus types in there, not less. There’s one good solution, which is to buy Intimate Hygiene Washes, particularly those with prebiotics or probiotics in them. The really high-end washes are pretty pricy and come in a foaming bottle but we can buy a foam-making bottle and pour (diluted) washing solution in there to max out our money, because the washing instructions pretty much always instruct users to foam before applying, which is tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy those at Walmart for less than $5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I’ve made my small bottle last me a whole six months, washing twice a day!$5 never went anywhere as far in my life as this)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advantages-of-not-being-malodorous&quot;&gt;Advantages of not being malodorous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mental Well-being – we can be further in harmony with our new anatomy after our painful rebirth, be more confident and not be so paranoid everyone is smelling fish when we enter the room.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better physical well-being – yes, not having a rash or stinky discharge is pretty nice, plus we don’t have to scrub our undies that hard. whew. 
as&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better love life – most lovers prefer ladybits which don’t smell offensive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-should-we-start-or-when-is-it-okay-to-use-a-vaginal-wash&quot;&gt;When should we start or when is it okay to use a vaginal wash?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise indicated by your doctor, a good time would be pretty close to the end of your antiobiotic dosage, or when the offensive smell / discharge starts to appear, or when your stitches stop oozing. Usually that would be around the 6 week mark upwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also never too late to use a vaginal wash, no matter how many years postop a person is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please report on your results after trying this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/health/2015/07/27/VaginalFlora/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/health/2015/07/27/VaginalFlora/</guid>
        
        <category>flora</category>
        
        <category>feminine</category>
        
        <category>hygiene</category>
        
        <category>wash</category>
        
        
        <category>health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Postopcare 101</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A community driven effort to share tips and tricks for the initial MTF SRS postop recovery period.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 23:24:44 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://postopcare.github.io/introduction/2015/07/26/welcome-to-postopcare/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://postopcare.github.io/introduction/2015/07/26/welcome-to-postopcare/</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
